August Jaccaci
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1895-1929, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
  - McCraigh, Elizabeth - MacVeagh, Charles, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 619-644) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    McKinlay, D. A. & Co.
    Macoll, D. S.
    MacVeagh, Charles
  - Madet, Dr. A., 1926-1929, (fr. 645-691) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Mann, Morgan - Mansfield, Bessie, 1903-1914, (fr. 692-759) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Mann, Morgan
    Mansfield, Bessie
  - Mansfield, Helen C. - Marbury, Elizabeth, 1904-1914, (fr. 760-810) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Mansfield, Helen C.
    Mansfield, Howard
    Manzi, Mr.
    Marbury, Elizabeth
  - Marcel, Pierre - Marillier, H. C., 1904-1913, (fr. 811-850) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Marcel, Pierre
    Marguiller, A.
    Marillier, H. C.
  - Markoe, Frances L. - Masi, Guiseppe, 1903-1909, (fr. 851-901) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Markoe, Frances L.
    Marks, Alfred
    Martin, W.
    Masi, Guiseppe
  - Marx, Roger, 1904-1908, undated, (fr. 860-914) (Box 3, Reel D122)
  - Mather, Frank Jewett, Jr., 1904-1914, undated, (2 folders; fr. 912-1028) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Mather, Katherine - Mena, Maria Christina, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 1029-1041) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Mather, Katherine
    Mayo, Lina L.
    Mead, William R.
    Meade, Larkin G.
    Mena, Maria Christina
  - Menotti, Mario - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1904-1907, undated, (fr. 1042-1075) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Menotti, Mario
    Merrill, L. K.
    Metropolitan Museum of Art
  - Meynell, Everett, 1903, undated, (fr. 1076-1090) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Michel, Andre - Millet, Francis Davis, 1904-1912, (fr. 1091-1135) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Michel, Andre
    Michou, R.
    Miller, Jacob W.
    Millet, Francis Davis
  - Mirande - Mitchell, J. K., 1897-1921, undated, (fr. 1136-1160) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Mirande
    Mirbeau, Octave
    Missouri-Lincoln Trust Co.
    Mitchell, J. A.
    Mitchell, J. K.
  - Moes, Ernst W., 1904-1908, (fr. 1161-1201) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Monnet, J. B. - Morgan, J. P., 1907-1921, (fr. 1202-1245) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Monnet, J. B.
    Moore, Helen
    Moore, Marion O.
    More, Paul Elmer
    Morgan, Ann
    Morgan, J. P.
  - Morris, Harrison - Morse, Edward L., 1903-1909, (fr. 1246-1275) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Morris, Harrison
    Morris, Mr.
    Morrow, William
    Morse, Edward L.
  - Morton, J. L. - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company, 1898-1913, (fr. 1276-1335) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Morton, J. L.
    Moseley, Julia Daniels
    Mosle, A. H.
    Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company
  - Nast-Kolb & Schumacher - Newman, May, 1904-1913, (fr. 1337-1372) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Nast-Kolb & Schumacher
    Neumann, Carl
    New Amsterdam Gas Company
    New York Public Library (1358-1359, also Reel D120: 1444-1455)
    New York Trust Company
    Newman, May
  - Newport, Mary Morgan - Norton, C. E. & Richard, 1897-1911, undated, (fr. 1373-1432) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Newport, Mary Morgan
    Norris, Charles G.
    North German Lloyd Street Company
    Norton, C. E. & Richard
  - O'Donovan, E. W. - Osborn, Alice, 1906-1920, undated, (fr. 1434-1465) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    O'Donovan, E. W.
    Of, George F.
    Ogden & Clarkson
    Ogier, E.
    Olinsky, Ivan
    Oppenheim, Bertha
    Oppenheim, Nathan
    Osborn, Alice
  - Pach, Walter - Parsons, Mabel, 1897-1913, undated, (fr. 1467-1497) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Pach, Walter
    Page, Helen
    Page, Marie K.
    Painter, M. W.
    Palmer, Frederick
    Parish, Susan L.
    Parson, Arthur Jeffray
    Parsons, Mabel
  - Paper Company correspondence, 1903-1910, (fr. 1655-1696) (Box 3, Reel D123)
  - Parsons, Samuel, 1897-1912, (2 folders; fr. 1498-1547) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Paton, David, 1910-1912, undated, (fr. 1548-1631) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Paton, Peggie, 1911, (fr. 1632-1649) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Paton, William Agnew, 1907-1913, undated, (3 folders; fr. 1650-1808) (Box 3, Reel D121)
  - Peabody, Malvina A. - Pennell, Elizabeth R., 1897, 1904-1906, undated, (fr. 1809-1828) (Box 3, Reel D121)
    Peabody, Malvina A.
    Peacock, Mr.
    Peck, Howard
    Peixotto, Ernest & Mary
    Pennell, Elizabeth R.
  - Pennington, Harper, 1903-1911, (3 folders; fr. 1829-1836, Reel D122: fr. 1-125) (Box 3, Reel D121-122)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts - Peterson, Antoinette R., 1897-1907, (fr. 126-151) (Box 3, Reel D122)
    Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts (Reel D121: fr. 1814)
    Perkins, F. Mason
    Peterson, Antoinette R.
  - Pfister Binding Company, 1907-1915, (4 folders; fr. 152-279) (Box 3, Reel D122)
  - Philbin, Eugene A. - Phillips, Claude, 1904-1910, (fr. 280-300) (Box 3, Reel D122)
    Philbin, Eugene A.
    Phillips, Claude
  - Phillips, John S., 1912-1913, undated, (fr. 301-326) (Box 3, Reel D122)
  - Pick, Robert F. - Pope, Arthur, 1897-1913, undated, (fr. 327-359) (Box 3, Reel D122)
    Pick, Robert F.
    Pillot, Mrs.
    Pine, John B.
    Pinkham, Lydia E.
    Piping Rock Club
    Pope, Arthur
  - Pope, Theodate, 1906-1913, undated, (2 folders; fr. 360-485) (Box 3, Reel D122)
  - Potter, Bessie - Pupin, Michael, 1896-1921, (fr. 486-534) (Box 3, Reel D122)
    Potter, Bessie
    Powell, Bradford
    Powell, William H.
    Prangey, Col.
    Prichard, W. S.
    Prime, Lena E.
    Prinet, Rene X.
    Pritchard, A. G. & Co.
    Proctor, Margaret D.
    Proctor, A. Phimister
    Pupin, Michael
  - Raffaelli, Jean Francois - Randall-MacIver, 1907, undated, (fr. 536-542) (Box 3, Reel D122)
    Raffaelli, Jean Francois
    Randall-MacIver
  - Rankin, William, 1906-1914, undated, (3 folders; fr. 543-702) (Box 3, Reel D122)
  - Rawlinson, W. J. - Rhinelander, Edith, 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 703-729) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Rawlinson, W. J.
    Reinach, Solomon
    Reuterdahl, Henry
    Reymond, Marcel
    Rhinelander, Edith
  - Ricci, Corrado, 1904, (fr. 730-754) (Box 4, Reel D122)
  - Richards, C. B. & Co. - Richter, J. Paul, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 755-807) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Richards, C. B. & Co.
    Richmond, George H.
    Richter, J. Paul
  - Robinson - Robinson, H. E., 1897-1912, undated, (fr. 808-856) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Robinson, (?)
    Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt
    Robinson, H. E.
  - Rochement, Ruth de - Rogers, John B. & Co., 1904-1913, (fr. 857-979) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Rochement, Ruth de
    Rogers, Winthrop L.
    Rogers, John B. & Co.
  - Rooses, Max, 1904, (fr. 980-1010) (Box 4, Reel D122)
  - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit - Russell, E. E. M., 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 1011-1023) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Roosevelt, Edith Kermit
    Rudd, Henry W.
    Rushforth, G. McNeil
    Russell, (?)
    Russell, E. E. M.
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1913-1914, (fr. 1024-1080) (Box 4, Reel D122)
  - Saladin, H. - Schmidt, W., 1904-1910, (fr. 1082-1126) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Saladin, H.
    Salvatore, Victor D.
    Schermerhorn, Alfred E.
    Schiller, Max
    Schley, George B.
    Schmidt, W.
  - Schuyler, M. - Shipman, B. J., 1898-1914, undated, (fr. 1127-1166) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Schuyler, M.
    Scribner, Charles
    Scudder, Janet
    Seaman, Stephen
    Seymour, George D.
    Shean, Charles M.
    Sheldon, Christine L.
    Sherman, Frederic F.
    Shipman, B. J.
  - Sickert, Bernhard, 1903-1908, (6 folders; fr. 1167-1598) (Box 4, Reel D122)
  - Sickert, Robert - Sincerbeaux, Charles S., 1909-1912, (fr. 1599-1624) (Box 4, Reel D122)
    Sickert, Robert
    Sincerbeaux, Charles S.
  - Siren, Oswald, 1908-1914, (3 folders; fr. 1625-1840) (Box 4, Reel D122)
  - Siren, Oswald, Lecture Tour, 1913-1914, (2 folders; fr. 1-117) (Box 4, Reel 123)
  - Six, J. - Smith, Gertrude Robinson, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 118-146) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Six, J.
    Sizeranne, Robert de la
    Slade, Charles M. H.
    Slater, Ellen
    Smith, Gertrude Robinson
  - Smith, A. Hammond - Smith Premier Typewriter Co., 1908-1914, (fr. 147-159) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Smith, A. Hammond
    Smith Premier Typewriter Co.
  - Snyder, Carl, 1903-1904, (6 folders; fr. 160-743) (Box 4, Reel D123)
  - Solinas, G. - Spielmann, M. H., 1903-1913, undated, (fr. 744-784) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Solinas, G.
    Somerset Laundry
    Spielmann, M. H.
  - Spofford, Ellen B. - Starkweather, C. C., 1896-1910, (fr. 785-826) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Spofford, Ellen B.
    Sprague, Mr.
    Squiers, Edward C.
    Starkweather, C. C.
  - Stead, Amelia F. T. - Stimson, Daniel M., 1897-1913, undated, (fr. 827-865) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Stead, Amelia F. T.
    Steffens, J. Lincoln
    Steinman, E.
    Stephens, F. G.
    Stern, Walter T.
    Sterners, (?)
    Stillwell, Lewis B.
    Stimson, Daniel M.
  - Stone, Herbert S. - Sturgis, Russell, 1896-1913, (fr. 871-885) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Stone, Herbert S.
    Story, Richard
    Straight, Dorothy
    Strean, Maria J.
    Sturgis, Russell
  - Swift, Eliza, Frederick, & Lexie - Swift, Samuel, 1907-1913, undated, (fr. 886-937) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Swift, Eliza, Frederick & Lexie
    Swift, Samuel
  - Tack, Augustus V., 1910-1913, undated, (fr. 939-966) (Box 4, Reel D123)
  - Tallman, C. H. - Texas Company, 1897-1913, undated, (fr. 967-999) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Tallman, C. H.
    Tarbell, Ida M. & Clara
    Tavernier, Paul
    Taylor, Anne
    Taylor, Carl
    Teixeira de Mattos, Alexander
    Terry, Mrs. Charles, Jr.
    Texas Company
  - Thomas, Linda - Tracy, Marguerite, 1904-1914, (fr. 1000-1044) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Thomas, Linda
    Thomson, D. Croal
    Tiffany & Company
    Tone, Aileen
    Tonides, J.
    Townsend, C. H.
    Townsend, James W.
    Tracy, Marguerite
  - Trowbridge, Alexander B. - Twombly, Florence, 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 1045-1069) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Trowbridge, Alexander B.
    Trumbull, Anni E.
    Tschudi, Hugo von
    Tuffier, (?)
    Twombly, Florence
  - U. S. Express Company - Valentiner, William R., 1904-1914, undated, (fr. 1071-1126) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    U. S. Express Company
    Vachon, Marius
    Valentiner, William R.
  - Van der Hoeven, W. - Van Ness, Iola, 1904-1912, (fr. 1127-1149) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Van der Hoeven, W.
    Van Dyke, John C.
    Van Horne, Sir William
    Van Ingen, W. B.
    Van Ness, Iola
  - Van Rensselaer, M. G., undated, (2 folders; fr. 1150-1269) (Box 4, Reel D123)
  - Vaux, C. B. - Venturi, A., 1896-1904, (fr. 1270-1299) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Vaux, C. B.
    Venturi, A.
  - Veth, Jan - Von Glehn, Wilfrid, 1904-1913, undated, (fr. 1300-1329) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Veth, Jan
    Vigouroux, John
    Von Glehn, Wilfrid
  - Waern, Cecelia - Walton, William, 1906-1913, undated, (fr. 1331-1385) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Waern, Cecelia
    Wagner, William Van
    Wallis, Whitworth
    Walton, William
  - Ward, Humphrey - Warner, S. L., 1904-1912, undated, (fr. 1386-1446) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Ward, Humphrey
    Ward, De Wit C.
    Ward Memorial book
    Warner, S. L.
  - Watts, G. F. - Weitenkampf, Frank, 1898-1913, undated, (fr. 1447-1487) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Watts, G. F.
    Wauters, A. J.
    Weale, W. H. J.
    Weeks, E. L.
    Weir, J. Alden
    Weisbach, Werner
    Weitenkampf, Frank
  - West Point Army Mess - Winter, Edwin W., 1897-1909, undated, (fr. 1488-1534) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    West Point Army Mess
    Westminster, Duke of
    Wharton, Mrs.
    Wheelock, Ellen
    Whibley, Charles
    White, Elizabeth C.
    White, William Allen
    White Star Line
    Whitney, Helen Hay
    Willett, Henry
    Williams, C. C.
    Williams, Jesse Lynch
    Windsor Trust Company
    Winter, Edwin W.
  - Witt, Robert C. - Wood, C. E. S., 1896-1914, undated, (fr. 1535-1564) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Witt, Robert C.
    Woermann, Karl
    Wolfe, Elsie de
    Wood, C. E. S.
  - Wood, L. Hollingsworth - Wright, Thomas, 1904-1913, (fr. 1565-1602) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Wood, L. Hollingsworth
    Woodberry Society
    Woodbury, Mrs. Marcia O.
    Wright, Charles Lennox
    Wright, Thomas
  - Ymamura, Jishichi - Zogbaum, R. F., 1907-1914, undated, (fr. 1604-1611) (Box 4, Reel D123)
    Ymamura, Jishichi
    Young, A. Murray
    Zogbaum, R. F.
  - Unidentified letters, 1896-1913, undated, (fr. 43-86) (Box 4, Reel D124)
  - Miscellaneous Business Correspondence, A-Z, 1903-1914, undated, (2 folders; fr. 96-237) (Box 4, Reel D124)
  - Correspondence about Printing and Publishing Noteworthy Paintings, 1904-1907, (4 folders) (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
- Legal Files, 1895-1911, undated, Series 2:; (Box 5; 4 folders)
  Legal files include a mortgage contract for the August F. Jaccaci Company as well as Jaccaci legal agreements related to his company and the rights for his book Noteworthy Paintings. Also found are legal agreements made by John La Farge concerning his artwork and publication rights in the book. This series also contains court documents concerning the theft of prints and negatives of artwork.
  - August F. Jaccaci Company Mortgage Contract, 1906 (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
  - August Jaccaci Legal Agreements, 1907-1911, (fr. 87-95) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - John La Farge Legal Agreements, 1895, 1897, undated, (fr. 1456-1460) (Box 5, Reel D120)
  - Court Documents, William A. Cooper v. William G. Gray, circa 1905 (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
- Writings and Notes, 1903-1914, undated, Series 3:; (Box 5; 0.6 linear feet)
  This series contains writings and notes by August Jaccaci, John La Farge, and others. Included are Jaccaci's lists of works of art, photographs, essays, and payments for his Noteworthy Paintings project. Also included are Jaccaci's notes on his research of Martin, King of Aragon & Sicily, and other miscellaneous notes.
  Writings by John La Farge include notes and a complete typescript of his book One Hundred Masterpieces of Painting, published posthumously in 1912. Included are notes written by others about the publication of the work. Also found are notes and drafts for a series of lectures La Farge gave on the Barbizon School of France at the Art Institute of Chicago known as the Scammon lectures, and miscellaneous notes about his artwork.
  Writings by others include draft essays written by various art historians and critics such as Arsène Alexandre and Gabriel Mourey for Jaccaci's book Noteworthy Paintings. Many of the essays have handwritten annotations. Also found in this series are sample page proofs from Gillis Press, the proposed printer of the book, as well as vouchers of payment to the writers of the essays for the book. Researchers should note that writings about artwork from American art collections are also found in Series 4: Art Collection Research Files.
  - By August Jaccaci (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Lists and Notes Regarding Noteworthy Paintings, 1903-1904, (3 folders; fr. 566-853) (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Notes on Martin, King of Aragon & Sicily, 1908, undated, (fr. 895-920) (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated, (fr. 1-42) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - By John La Farge (Box 5)
    - Notes and Drafts of "The Scammon Lectures", 1903, (3 folders; fr. 1507-1713) (Box 5, Reel D120)
    - Notes and Drafts of 100 Masterpieces of Painting, 1911, undated, (2 folders; fr. 921-1159) (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Miscellaneous Notes about his work, 1907-1914, (fr. 1461-1506) (Box 5, Reel D120)
  - Writings by Others, (fr. 238-565, 1160-1508) (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essay, "'Marin' by Claude Monet" by Arsene Alexandre, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essay, "Little Studies of Velasquez" by Mayer, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essays by Gabriel Mourey, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essay, "Giotto", by J. Paul Richter, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essays by W. Roberts, 1913-1914, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Manuscript, "Catalogue: De Dessins Anciens", by E. Rodriguez, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Manuscript, "Two in the Abbruzzi", undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essays by Various Authors, 1903-1909, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Essay Fragments by Various Authors, undated (Box 5, Reel D124)
    - Unidentified Writings, 1913, undated, (fr. 854-881) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - Gillis Press Sample Book Proof Pages, undated (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
  - Vouchers of Payment to Writers, 1509-1549)undated, (fr. 1509-1549) (Box 5, Reel D124)
- Art Collection Research Files, 1889, 1892, 1903-1914, undated, Series 4:; (Box 5-7; 2.0 linear feet)
  This series consists of research files about American art collections and individual works of art that were to be featured in August Jaccaci's book Noteworthy Paintings in Private American Collections. Collections and collectors covered include Isabella Stewart Gardner, J. Pierpont Morgan, Henry Clay Frick, John Hay, William H. Vanderbilt, Peter A. B. Widener, and others. Arranged alphabetically by collector name, the files contain a variety of research materials that often include manuscript and typescript essays about the collection and individual works of art, notes, and scattered photographs. Most of the photographs of artwork from these art collections can be found in Series 5.2: Photographs of artwork. Essays were written by prominent art historians and artists, including Kenyon Cox, Harper Pennington, Samuel Isham, Max Friedlander, Ernst Moes, as well as many others.
  - R. B. Angus Collection, 1904, undated, (2 folders; fr. 1550-1628) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - George F. Baker Collection, undated, (fr. 1629-1643) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - Charles T. Barney Collection, undated, (fr. 1644-1664) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - August Belmont Collection, undated, (fr. 1665-1739) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - Chauncy J. Blair Collection, undated, (fr. 1740-1774) (Box 5, Reel D124)
  - Burke Collection, undated, (fr. 1775) (Box 6, Reel D124)
  - Byers Collection, undated, (fr. 1776-1789) (Box 6, Reel D124)
  - Theodore M. Davis Collection, undated, (2 folders; fr. 1790-1834, Reel D125: fr. 1-29) (Box 6, Reel D124-125)
  - Drummond Collection, undated, (fr. 40-42) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - William Elkins Collection, 1904, undated, (fr. 43-56) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - James W. Ellsworth Collection, 1889, undated, (4 folders; fr. 57-128) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - Henry C. Frick Collection, 1908-1914, undated, (7 folders; fr. 129-596) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - Isabella Stewart Gardner Collection, 1903-1906, undated, (4 folders; fr. 597-841) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - J. W. Gates Collection, undated, (fr. 842-890) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - George J. Gould Collection, 1904, undated, (2 folders; fr. 891-975) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - L. C. Hanna Collection, 1913, (fr. 976-981) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - Henry O. Havemeyer Collection, undated, (fr. 982-990) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - John Hay Collection, undated, (fr. 991-1013) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - J. J. Hill Collection, 1892, 1903, 1913, undated, (4 folders; fr. 1014-1252) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - Charles L. Hutchinson Collection, 1904, undated, (12 folders; fr. 1253-1476) (Box 6, Reel D125)
  - John G. Johnson Collection, undated, (11 folders; fr. 1478-1638, D126: fr. 1-265) (Box 6-7, Reel D125-D126)
  - Lodge Collection, undated, (fr. 266-268) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Frank G. Logan Collection, undated, (fr. 269-290) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Samuel Mather Collection, undated, (fr. 683-688) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Cyrus McCormick Collection, 1904, undated, (fr. 291-314) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - J. H. McFadden Collection, 1913, undated, (fr. 315-438) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Emerson McMillin Collection, undated, (2 folders; fr. 439-682) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - J. Pierpont Morgan Collection, 1907, (fr. 689-692) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Horace Morison Collection, 1912, (fr. 693-697) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Alfred Atmore Pope Collection, undated, (fr. 698-721) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Ross Collection, undated, (fr. 722-732) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Martin A. Ryerson Collection, 1904, undated, (fr. 733-784) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - A. A. Sprague Collection, undated, (fr. 785-794) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Charles W. Taft Collection, undated, (fr. 795-813) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Terrell Collection, undated, (fr. 814-840) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Edward R. Thomas Collection, undated, (fr. 841-851) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - William H. Vanderbilt Collection, undated, (2 folders; fr. 852-923) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Sir William Van Horne Collection, 1913, undated, (3 folders; fr. 924-990) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Wade Collection, undated, (fr. 991-1045) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Harris Whittemore Collection, undated, (fr. 1046-1062) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Peter A. B. Widener Collection, 1905-1914, undated, (6 folders; fr. 1063-1315) (Box 7, Reel D126)
  - Miscellaneous Art Collection Material, undated (Box 7, Reel unfilmed)
- Photographs, 1904-1912, 1928-1935, undated, Series 5:; (Box 7-8; 0.4 linear feet)
  The Photographs series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Subseries 5.1: Photographs of Stencils, 1928-1935, undated
  Subseries 5.2: Photographs of Artwork, 1904-1912, undated
  - Photographs of Stencils, 1928-1935, undated, Subseries 5.1:; (fr. 1316-1471)
    Photographs of stencils includes a folder with an essay and notes about stencils, a folder with photographs of stenciling tools and folders containing photographs of stencil designs and photographs of stenciled walls and floors from historic homes, primarily in the New England region.
    - Documentation about Stencils, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Stenciling Tools, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Fruit Basket Stencils, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Shell Stencils, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Fruit Stencils, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Miscellaneous Stencils, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Floor Stencils at Atkins House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Barry House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Buchanan House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at John Coolidge House, 1928, 1934, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Joshua Eaton House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Lynde House, 1935, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Mowry Tavern, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Rhodes House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Ebenezer Robinson House, undated (Box 7, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Slack House, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Elisha Smith House, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Wickham-Valentine House, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Noah Wood House, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
    - Wall Stencils at Miscellaneous Houses, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
    - Stencils at Unidentified Houses, undated (Box 8, Reel D126)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1904-1912, undated, Subseries 5.2:
    Photographs of Artwork include black and white photographs of famous paintings found in some of the collections listed in Series 4: Art Collection Research Files. Some of the photographs are labeled and attributed to certain collections, though some are not labeled.
    - Miscellaneous Photographs of Artwork, 1904-1912, undated, (8 folders) (Box 8, Reel unfilmed)